TYRONE W. NOLASCO

tyronewessnolasco@gmail.com | (+61) 401 687 774 | Brisbane, 4077

G: https://github.com/sh1ggy

L: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyrone-nolasco/

SUMMARY

Based in Brisbane and working as a Systems Support Specialist at Sonic IT with a proficiency in verbose incident documentation and communications under the pressure of customer and stakeholder expectations. I have a desire to further my technical capabilities as a programmer, improve my ability to communicate as well as take advantage of opportunities to work outside of my comfort zone.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sonic IT May. 2022 - Current

System Support Specialist

Brisbane, Queen Street

- Responsible for troubleshooting medical software supported by Sonic IT to resolve tickets raised by medical sites across Australia, achieving an average of 6+ ticket resolutions per day.
- Maintenance of case-by-case incident documentation and team-wide knowledge articles as a part of a collaborative effort to document the support process for 30+ different pieces of software.
- Management of at least 1 critical incident per week that requires instant action and outward communication to affected users.
- Responsible for engaging with internal Sonic IT teams & external vendors via thorough communication to assist with incident resolution and management of critical incidents.

Wings Education

Aug. 2021 – May. 2022

IT Support & Social Media Lead

Brisbane, Fortitude Valley

- Managed and developed PHP-based Learning Management System website using Moodle & SQL that aimed to increase staff and student productivity.
- Administered IT hardware and software support to maintain the company's 2 sites of computer labs
- Led the production of at least 1 video/week & 3 social media designs/day for company marketability.
- Mentored cohorts of 2 3 IT interns every 4 months in basic IT troubleshooting, social media design and LMS maintenance skills in addition to teaching essential communication skills.
- Composed major pieces of internal company documentation that the company still uses today.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Queensland University of Technology

2018 - 2021

Bachelor of Information Technology (Distinction) - Computer Science Major

GPA: 5.875

Minors: Engineering Foundations & Mobile App Development

Social Clubs: UQ Computing Society, CODE Network

INTERESTS & SKILLS

Skills: Documentation, written communication, incident management, systems diagramming, design **Programming Languages & Technologies:** JavaScript, React, React Native, NodeJS, NextJS,

TypeScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, C#, C

Interests: Hackathons, game jams, DDR, rhythm games

2022 - Current Not a Key Logger (NAKL)

TypeScript, NextJS & React Native

Serverless peer-to-peer messaging and file transferring platform

- A hackathon turned long-term project, creating a platform designed for two parties to exchange files & text messages through a serverless peer-to-peer connection.
- Leading the design, use-case diagramming and documentation related to the project.
- Self-managed project, using Trello Kanban board and a iterative weekly agile framework to ensure constant progression and reflection.

https://github.com/ProPablo/nakl

2021 - 2023 Redland Museum Display and Information Guidance System (DIGS)

TypeScript, React & React Native

Continuation of the QUT Capstone Project outside of the scope of university work.

- Finalised an ongoing project in 2 and a half years, rebuilding the 3 year old DIGS administrative portal and application with modern technologies and frameworks.
- Led the project as an acting project manager responsible for the delegation of tasks that aligned with project scope following an iterative development framework.
- Managed project expectations with the Project Owner via regular online meetings, email correspondence and onsite visits.
- Composed visualisations of technical system architecture and wrote significant client-facing documentation & reports.

2023 **keyDOTboard**

TypeScript, NextJS & Tauri

An RFID card password manager

- Made as a part of the 2023 Arduino Hackathon, with continued works for two weeks following the event to fully complete the project
- Uses a TailwindCSS & NextJS front-end to load binaries onto an ESP32/Arduino card reader back-end to handle password input and manage different RFID cards

https://github.com/sh1ggy/keyDOTboard

REFERENCES

Russell Dinte:

Project Manager & IT at Redland Museum

E: russdinte@bigpond.com

P: +61 7 3286 3494

Anhad Ahuja:

Programming Teammate
E: anhadrs@gmail.com

P: +61 490 779 437